<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
<name>[RH2] BCD: First Aid</name>
<author>Chicken Plucker, Taranchuk</author>
	<packageId>RH2.BCDs.First.Aid</packageId>
	<modDependencies>
        <li>
            <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
            <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
            <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
            <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
        </li>
    </modDependencies>
	<supportedVersions>
	<li>1.2</li>
	<li>1.3</li>
	<li>1.4</li>
	<li>1.5</li>
	<li>1.6</li>
	</supportedVersions>
<description>Save precious time during the golden hour of survival with this first aid mod!

"BCDs" also known as the Battlefield Casualty Drills are a series of emergency medical procedures for the basic soldier.

First aid allows your pawns to tend to downed casualties on the spot. If medical resources or a hospital bed is available nearby, the medic will utilize these before hastily performing first aid.

The following mod adds:
- New right click option on downed pawns to "Perform first aid"
- First aid tends to downed pawns without a bed
- First aid will allow the medic to grab the nearest medicine resource, otherwise they will tend to the casualty with no medicine
- Can be used on enemy pawns and friendlies
- First aid tending speed is faster than normal tending, however the quality of tending is reduced

What is BCD?
Battlefield Casualty Drills, medical procedures in the event of a casualty in combat.

What is First Aid?
Medical treatment given to a casualty or injured person until further medical help is available

What's the difference between this mod, the 1.3 tending feature and the "Stabilize Here" mod?
- First Aid tend speed is 200% faster (scaling is based on pawn's medical ability)
- First Aid tend quality is -25% worse (scaling is based on pawn's medical ability)
- Pawn searches for nearby medical items, or ones in their inventory (uses the highest quality of medicine, unless forbidden)
- Presentation and art style

Combat Extended Compatible?
Unknown.

Credits:
Taranchuk - C#
Linkolas - Author of "Stabilize Here"</description>
</ModMetaData>